[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
[Music]
with ourselves
my friends it's me and it's you
and we're listening to the junkyard love
podcast where at the
intro i like to add some form of new
knowledge new information
new perspective a new talk a passage
from a book
a book something somewhere to change or
view or maybe
make you think differently about
something most of the time my guest does
not know or really have any affiliation
of course with
the intro part so i just want to make
that clear i just kind of randomly put
in some
my thoughts at that time for the intro
before the guest i just want to enrich
the listener with new information so
when they're out there kind of looking
for something to feed their brains they
don't have to
default to you know watching parks and
rec for the millionth time
or watching whatever youtube suggests
next
guilty and guilty myself so
this week's recommendation um is
it is titled how the evolution of porn
changed adolescence that's why megan
moss
m a it's just a nice perspective flip i
think it's something that we should look
at
we should have a look at this whole porn
thing you know i've flipped my
perspective on it over the last couple
years myself
i think it's important to talk about i
think we should have room for the
uncomfortable conversations right
so enjoy the episode take care of
yourselves drink
dat water let's go
knowledge is power
first things first my man cheers i'm
running across the table cheers
it's good to see you buddy good to see
you too
i'm gonna struggle with this chair i can
hear it creaking dude it ain't as bad as
the last one i'm always moving
the other one yeah i know i'm always
twitching and fidgeting into
adhd the last one would just randomly
just
slide right on down so uh i hate those
chairs yeah dude you just
i know it'd be funny i'd be in like a
heated conversation or not heated you
know but just like a serious
conversation
and we're up on this table to where it's
we're both max height and then the
guests would just
like it's some sort of like power move
on my end i think i'm just like yeah i
just want to make sure you know that
your chair's lower than mine
for sure for sure it's mad weird i i
hate those chairs
because you're just chilling and all of
a sudden you just drop
it's like makes you feel so heavy
was that me dude i've got chairs
upstairs the dining room table chairs
are like they're a danger every time
that somebody new comes over it's like
shane and i are just watching like hawks
to make sure like
do we need to warn them in a second yeah
like we always say watch out for that
chair like
eventually we're just gonna get new
chairs we probably should but until the
time being somebody's gonna bust it
oh sometimes you just gotta let it play
out yeah yeah see what happens
all right bro so it's been a while i
kind of want something to just like
catch up a little bit
um what have you been up to the last few
months like what's what's quarantine
been like
to you man quarantine's been crazy
um i work from home
like as you know i'm a school high
school counselor so
um we haven't been allowed in school and
um so everything we do is from home in
my apartment
and i know it's been an adjustment man
like
um i'm i'm a i don't have like a family
you know like i live by myself in a one
bedroom apartment
so just by yourself like
all day like working like working from
home is dope don't get me wrong but like
during quarantine when you can't do
anything i mean i still did stuff here
and there but
for like those first month and a half i
was really just chilling and
um after a while it started starting to
get to me i'm not even gonna lie man it
was like it's all of us
you can't i think i went through like a
three day span where
i didn't even leave my front door and i
was like
on the third day i was like yeah i gotta
get out of here bro like i'm going crazy
i'm i'm i'm going nuts well and then not
being able to like
you know like i don't know how many
hours or how exactly you had to work but
not being able to like separate your
work from your home
like especially if you're just like you
know i'm pretty lucky that i have like
a ton of space here right able to be
like all right i can turn it off and
just go upstairs and watch tv and [__]
but
um megan elam she was down in in
portland and they basically like
i think they had to like move their
computers and [__] like
um it's probably like a safety security
sort of thing so they can't just like
you log into whatever you want on your
personal computer that's probably not
allowed
but so they had to have like you know
their headsets their whole like desk set
up
and she lives in just a studio right and
so she was just
she was going straight crazy because
it's like when you're not like you
you're just in the same exact room
at all times you could turn around and
see the same exact thing right
like whether you're working or you're
trying to chill it'd be hard to turn it
off
it's for sure it's it's important to get
that uh that scenery
change you know like that that's how we
separate
work from home you know like when you go
to your job like
that scenery what's what's around you
what you're what's surrounding you
right that's work when you go home
different scenery different
vibe different environment when you're
in the same vibe all day
like home is now work and work is now
home
yeah like it starts to it starts to mess
you up after a while
yeah it's kind of weird you know like we
do kind of
we all we have like kind of
personalities that we turn on and like
you know parts of ourselves that we're
like making sure we're sharpening in
certain areas so like
when you go to work it's like all right
turn on yeah like like let's be school
counselor like let's be the most
this that i can be right but when you're
at home it's probably like a little
different you know because you're also
trying to it's your
it's your home it's safety like i'm
being mad yeah yeah i'm being me but
also trying to do my job not in my job
setting
yeah so i don't know
you know how it is we're we all carry so
many different personas
so many different personalities like
we we're all so many different people in
one it and it's crazy like
we all know ourselves we we can all say
we're we're this type
we're this person but we carry so many
different
characters in our in our brain and we we
we're chameleons
we we mold to some no matter we mold to
the environment we're around
yeah you know unless you're like a super
narcissistic
narcissistic person like you're gonna
you're gonna mold to whatever
environment you're around because you
want to blend in
that's this is human nature yeah you
want to belong yeah
you're gonna you're gonna assimilate
yeah i think that
uh you know i always think of it
as uh back when i first started working
um
16 17 i was working out like pacsun
clothing store
and then munition fuel um like a
moto lifestyle store and just thinking
about the
like even as a person behind the counter
like you like people walk in i talk
about the example of
you know like an older lady walks in by
herself or an older old lady walks in
with her young grandson
i'm like hey ma'am how are you today and
you know i'm more gentle in my demeanor
well
you know in 30 minutes once she's done
she's bought her stuff whatever see you
later have a great day
um like three skateboarder dudes walk in
like they just got out of school i'm
like what up my dudes
how you doing like you know we have
these different um
i think that we're you know we're always
trying to be or try to communicate
that with this consistent one thing and
it like puts a kind of a hold on all of
us like
because we you know because someone
always expects you to be that thing
or they they expect you to be something
else in certain environments it's
we're impressive [__] creatures when
it comes to this stuff yeah
there's so there's so much to this man
and and it's crazy like
i feel like we
we change and evolve so many times and
adapt to whatever environment we're in
so whenever you're like
around people you're not with all the
time and
like one time you give them one persona
in the next
it's another but it's because you're in
a different environment a different vibe
people think you're fake it's like i'm
not fake i'm just
i'm just i'm just in a different head
space i'm in a different environment so
i might have been wildin over here this
time but
right this vibe's chill so i'm chilling
and it's like i'm not i'm not changing
i'm not being fake i'm
i'm just adapting to where i am and
what's going on at this point in time
right it's an important like skill
almost to sharpen and
you know i think on the flip side when
other people around you are doing it i
think like everybody could be a little
more lenient almost like
okay like you're just you're just in
that vibe okay like you know
we're always trying to understand each
other anyway but we could really have
some leeway when we let each other
just like i think i kind of got you
figured out but i also know that i don't
and that's all right
you're just trying to live your life
yeah i don't i wouldn't want to figure
anyone out
right when you figure someone out it's
like where do you
like what's like what's the yeah like
snacks like you
you i just like know you like this is
all i'm gonna know you as forever
you know what i'm saying yeah i feel
like especially over the years you know
it's like shaylee and i've been together
for like almost 10 years
and you know i've changed so much in the
last couple years
but there's also like even before that
there's plenty of sides i mean that like
she doesn't know and there's plenty of
sides of her that like i don't know and
then
we also just getting older together like
we inevitably change
you know you get in your later 20s and
you start just looking at life
differently um
yeah it's super juicy i feel like that's
so good though for a relationship
standpoint
yeah it's just think about it like you
guys are still constantly like
learning who each other are like imagine
if you guys were the exact same like
when you guys started like you guys
would be you guys would be burnt out
yeah maybe a couple of little kids yeah
you guys you guys have run out of stuff
to talk about like
you have the same conversations forever
right but as you guys
both evolve and you guys both grow you
guys got
new jobs new lifestyles like
new questions are going to be raised new
conversations are gonna be raised it's
just
healthy for a relationship right and you
in
you know hanging out with different
people like you were saying who you're
around you know you're represented by
them like
um i think it's something like for me
at my age i started to discover like you
know that inevitable the thing you hear
that like you're the sum of the five
people you hang around or whatever
yeah and you're like that's like unreal
like you're like that that ain't true
and then you kind of start for me it's
like you kind of start thinking max like
oh man like
okay i was that when i was hanging out
with those with those people often or
you kind of just look at
you know me and the boys growing up as
15 16 year olds like of course
we're still boys yeah like when you
aren't hanging out all the time
there's like a i don't know there's like
a growth
that like i don't know you don't go back
to hanging out with your boys and become
the exact
same person you were when you're 16 when
you met yeah for sure
you know we're always adapted and grown
it's a beautiful thing to
like have i'm pretty lucky to have a lot
of the same homies
yeah yeah and we're just growing
together yeah yeah do you
do have you felt that like your friend
group like you guys have grown over the
years in different ways like changed oh
you watched it
man my whole friend group word is
everyone's doing their own thing like so
many of us are
doing completely different things but we
still get together and vibe out like
yeah
let's do all that like so many different
careers in my friend group so many
different
like it's crazy like
i don't even know how to notice that
like we just just
it all works yeah like what was it all
right so if you had to go in the form of
if you're describing it to somebody
telling them what clique you were in
what was your high school like
what was your homies like oh man like i
was i feel like i was like this
i was pretty all over you know i liked
everybody but i was a skater inherently
yeah
i i don't really i don't know
i mean i'm sure some people would say i
was gonna click but
i [__] with everybody dude yeah like i
loved everyone like
i say all the time like the people i
missed the most in high school were like
acquaintances like not my best homies
but dudes i
i knew that i would never see again
after high school
like looking back like those are the
dudes i always knew i was gonna miss the
most
and i do because like you're always
gonna have your boys like you're always
gonna have your best friends like
not to downplay their relationship but
like you know they're always gonna be
there
right but so like the friendships i
cherished the most were like
the dudes like i didn't kick it with
unless i was at school
right you know what i'm saying like yeah
like we didn't go home after school and
like kick it but
if we're in school or we got a class
together we're bullshitting and having a
great time it's almost like you
appreciate like you know you're not
gonna have a ton of time with this
person so you just
really appreciate what i got what they
can offer me and that and for i don't
know
for whatever reason i always
i always knew at that age that that was
a thing
and i wasn't going to be friends with
this dude or these dudes forever
or girls and so i always took advantage
of those
those friendships i feel like that's
pretty powerful a lot of us don't even
think that way and as far as
you know we're like oh we're living
through a lot of relationships and when
whether you're meeting people short term
or long term like you don't really think
of like
what is uh is this the last time i'm
gonna see this person right
is this is my last conversation with
this person can i say that it was
valuable
right that's kind of a weird thing yeah
because no no one's gonna
think like that yeah you know like
i mean if you're meeting someone at a
concert
like out of town yeah obviously it's
like
you could probably never see this person
again but it's locally like
you're going to see him again probably
yeah i was trying to i would try to
wonder
you know like how our town is different
than like bigger cities
when it comes to that stuff like small
town
do we assume that we're probably gonna
know them forever do we like do we try
to make the core so think about like new
york you like go to
one studio put you know one small place
in new york
you've got a uh you know a job that you
took out there you don't know anybody
out in new york like everybody you meet
is gonna be completely just the
interaction that you had with them oh
for sure but
in a small town it's like oh okay so
you're you're cousins to so and so and
you oh your dad's so and so it's like
you can find a connection with all these
people especially as you get older
uh it's it's interesting to think of of
the dynamic
here you know we have a small town but a
big small town
and to me it's really cool um
to just i don't know like like people
you always you always loved you always
like
got along with them but then you see
them like as they get older and they
start to become
like a grown man grown woman and you're
like oh dude you're so cool
like you're awesome yeah i always saw
that part in you but now like you're
really expressing it and you're finding
a way for other people to see that part
of you it's dope seeing people evolve
man
it's fantastic it's crazy even people
that like
fell off for a little bit and they they
build their self back up this
is that's a thing about beauty that's
the [__] i love i love to see that
um but no that reminds me of the first
time we talked
like before you really kicked this
podcast off and deleted it and you
deleted our
our talk it's a good one too but uh now
i remember
we were talking um because we were
talking about bed
like best friends like small towns
compared to like bigger cities and
when i was at central washington uh
like we i always talk with other dudes
and like trying to fill them out and
they're like
blown away that i had more than like one
best friend
or two best friends right and i was like
that was the vibe from like every
every dude that was from like seattle or
tacoma or
any of those bigger cities and i was
like that's
crazy to me like you like you're gonna
sit here and tell me like you
you might be able to say you have one
best friend like yeah
like i i feel like i can say i have like
30 best friends
that are like dudes that i care about a
lot yeah and you've been to their house
and you met their
family like like i couldn't
imagine that like having one per like
imagine only hanging out with one person
like you guys are gonna hate each other
eventually
well i mean like brother and sister
relationship is a good example like you
love each other of course you love
hanging out with them but after a while
you just
like you just have little buttons that
you poke on each other exactly
that's just i mean that's life
you're not you're not gonna get it you
don't get along with someone percent of
the time like
that's not how it works yeah so it's
like
growing up in a small town like
you get to have all those friendships
and all those best friends and like
you just get to hang out with whatever
like vibe you're in
on that day like right this day i'm
feeling this homie
like he he's like his vibe is what i
need today
and the next day it might be someone
else yeah that's a beautiful thing
i feel like that and that goes back to
like the chameleon personality maybe a
lot of people in small towns are good at
chameleon personalities maybe that's a
nice trait because you have to like
everyone knows you like you can't
like you're gonna adapt to whoever
you're with right
like you can't be the same all the time
it's so true you know there's there's
like a consistency
there's thinking about just the sides of
ourselves because there's a consistency
that like
there is a you obviously a constant you
and you've got to like try to be true to
that self and try to figure out what
that is what that means to you
but otherwise it's like you're kind of
just trying to
enjoy life and trying to bump into
people and see how they're enjoying life
right right i guess i should back up a
little bit like
i'm not saying you can't be the same
morally
or like just like deep down like
obviously you can stay
100 without like right i'm saying like
as far as your vibe
like how like are you chill that day or
like you
you hyped that day like vibes change
we're like not not like who you are as a
per i'm not saying
like obviously you're going to be who
you are as a person but like right
your vibe that day like that that's the
chameleon like that's what's going to
change day to day like
you're going to be in a different mood
every day yeah well
in the when you get around people you
love like they're they're cool with that
they're like oh
you have an off day that's cool still up
yeah and they're gonna accept whatever
vibe you're in
and they're gonna adapt do you think
that like the people who
you know in a bigger town like where
they didn't have a ton of best friends
like do you think they felt um like
maybe a little more pressure to like
always be on like if you know because
exactly the comfort of all your exactly
exactly that's crazy
and that's got to wear you out yeah for
sure
like not being able to like
bounce back and forth you know like
always having to be this
like type a like what if it's a day you
need type b
yeah what if it's a day where you're
just hurting or you just you don't want
to be on but you got to fake it
right i think that i've seen
i've seen my my friend group
you know people that i've hung out with
like
you know since since we were young um
and like
you know you you hang out with them in
different ways too like i feel like
uh you know we go on a we go on a
boating trip i have a few friends that
we go on boating trip with
every year in uh like last
was it labor day or something we had
gone and i remember this moment of all
of us you know we're all like latter 30s
now we've been doing it for it for a
while we've been hanging out for a while
um many years but we had like a a day
where just for like an
hour we were you know we were drinking
and partying all day like having a great
time but just in the middle of the
of the lake on the boat we just turned
off and we started bullshitting and
for an hour we were talking about like
uh like our relationships with our
parents
we were talking about like what um like
just
more serious stuff like emotional things
like we're kind of swapping back it was
like this
homey council you know and uh you know
there's a lot of
if it's something that i value
much it's it's so cool to have um
i'm just i wonder if not a lot of people
have that
um and and i think that a lot of times
it's
it's like we're so afraid to have like
the weird conversations right we're like
right i don't want to show them that
side and we're like i don't want them to
think that i'm not tough or
right well that's the that's the
difference between
being around people that you know really
value
like what's going on in your life
you know what i mean like
like it's hard to have those
conversations when if you don't know
like if that person truly cares what
you're saying
[Music]
but when you're around those people that
like you know they're listening and you
know they
like they give a [__] and then and they
know you care
those are just easier conversations to
have
it's funny that as you were explaining
that to me i wasn't paying attention i
was trying to fix that later
at all times and i was just saying
that's kept rolling
but but that's that's the thing man like
you got to be able to trust one another
you got to be able to like
as you get older man you realize that
once you just try to like you start
having those conversations with your
homies or you start like asking them
like
hey bro like are you good do you need to
talk do you need to you know these
conversations that
are upbringing like our societal
upbringing like not just our individual
parents but like we just don't talk
about
the real [__] all the time like we're
not allowed to talk about i mean think
about 20 years ago like
anxiety and depression like 20 years ago
nobody really had anxiety and depression
or
or really knew about or how to talk
about it or whatever it was there
just people didn't know right and we we
probably had to keep it under the
surface
too we had to keep our faces on too much
yeah
yeah it's nice to grow and adapt
um for the
it bothers me every time when i can hear
that so loud in my ears it just throws
me for a loop man what is it
um i think it's just i think it's just
my mom upstairs running
running water i was just running through
the pipes but these mics just pick it up
like that
but i heard it earlier but i wasn't sure
what it was yeah i wish that my adhd is
like
pay attention pay attention bro be right
here for sure
but yeah man it's a it's a beautiful
thing to grow it's a beautiful thing to
change it's a beautiful thing to like
allow other people to grow and change
too
like you know like
just allowing ourselves to grow into
what we really want
you know because everybody sees you in a
certain light everybody sees each other
you see your homies i don't know like
like as much as you've seen your good
homies like be be [__] you know
be turds as much as like i've done the
same thing like there's also
for me i don't know you just get older
and i just start to see them more in the
light of like oh here's what you're
gonna accomplish
like you're going to do this thing and
you just you value it a lot more and so
you go into those conversations without
thinking you need to like meet them like
i was talking about the
the example of working at the store like
a grandma it's like okay i think i need
to like meet her
at her level of like i'm making this
assessment of looking at them and i'm
going to try to just be the person that
she needs me to be
but you know you can you can
get rid of all that man you can get rid
of the facades and just like talk to
your homies
something super valuable i think i think
the whole grammar thing
like interacting like
being polite stuff like that i think i
think we subconsciously
like put that on because there is a
little kid there and we subconsciously
like
want to show that kid like how to
interact with
like our uh our elders
that's very true you know like
an elder like i'm gonna i'm gonna show
this younger kid
like how you're supposed to treat him
hmm
yeah that is true because you think of
like how a kid with his own grandma
he's kind of a little turd you know
because his grandma yeah when he sees
another kid who thinks
you're a guy who he thinks is cool and
respectful to grandma
you know that is that's a good point
well when kids are always watching it's
always like
so it's like if you don't greet her that
way
the kid's gonna be like oh maybe maybe
that's how it's supposed to be
right i mean we don't realize that we're
doing it but even when i was younger
i mean i was always looking up to older
people trying to like mimic them
you know like i remember i was talking
about um with my homie dev
i had these two guys that lived across
the street from me when i was growing up
and uh they were twins and they were a
few years older than me and i knew that
i was like probably the most annoying
kid ever
but they were nice to me like they were
skateboarders too so
um like the things that you kind of try
to do to impress those people
and you don't realize but like you said
like they're always watching yeah
there's always somebody watching and
it's a good
it's a it's a good thing to like you
know put on yourself like don't put a
bunch of pressure on yourself but like
sometimes we can get in our own heads
and sometimes it's important to remember
you know hey somebody's watching
like there's kids watching they're
looking up to me they're looking for
guidance
you know i try to even the neighbor kid
across the street like i always try to
be polite to him but i always try to
like treat him like an adult you know
like i was
like hey man what's up how are you like
what's what's been going on with school
um i think that it's it's
our interactions with each other are so
interesting we don't really take a look
at them but
sometimes we get too caught up i think
in uh you see a young kid and it's like
the goo
gaga like you gotta treat you know
sometimes you can just treat him like a
person and just
be yourself for sure yeah uh what's your
all right let's wind back i want to get
i want to get the listeners because we
didn't
we didn't post the last one because i
[__] deleted it
i'm trying to make sure they know you a
little bit um
you went to central yeah how many years
you go to central
i went to central for two years for two
years what'd you study
uh interdisciplinary studies okay
psychosocial anthro
how many years ago uh i graduated in
yeah yesterday you graduated yesterday
in 2016. yeah oh wait i was like wait
hold up
oh dude yeah no i saw i saw it's
actually sad that uh
well i mean it's better than nothing i
guess but like uh they drove up and got
their diplomas
did you see that yeah that's a strange
thing this
what is what has been have you been
involved in any like the graduation
stuff for for the kids graduating high
school now
has it been like crazy weird for them
have you yeah yeah that's crazy
like there's like i feel bad that they
didn't get a ceremony i mean
they had a virtual one it was on kltv
but i mean
you only get one graduation so it's kind
of
a bummer that they didn't get a like a
actual ceremony you know it's funny we i
feel like when i was a when i was
graduating it was kind of this like
whatever like i guess i'll walk like it
was like this like i guess i'll do it
but you know
then you get up there and you're smiling
your ears and walking across that stage
like you could no doubt like
adapting up the teachers for sure yeah
you it's one of those things you
downplay until you're in the moment
then you then it hits you it's like
never going to see
80 of these people ever again in my life
like this is actually real like it's
real [__] like i should
probably care a little bit here right
dude i
i kind of wonder you know i just feel my
sense of
of like hope obviously like through you
know it's it's it changes and it adapts
and we
and we get used to whatever a normal is
but like first month of coronavirus and
everything was like shutting down
like man my hope in like i'm just like
what is going to happen for the future
like what am i
what should i be planning for like
because for me all my i work in live
events
i'm a gig worker like all my [__] got
cancelled and i'm like
i don't know like do i just hold tight
and then in a few months i'll start
doing the same thing or do i need to
shift or what's what's going on i can't
imagine
trying to plan your like future like i'm
ready for college
i'm ready for this next step in my life
like
these poor kids you know yeah so
it's a huge step and a huge next chapter
with
so many uncertainties so what do you
what do you think's gonna be obviously
because of this not just this but this
is obviously gonna cause like over the
next five
ten years like trickles in our education
system for sure
like so what are you what's your broad
predictions
here like what do you how do you think
um you know
teaching and schooling um even on
college level down below like
all of it like do you do you think
there's anything for sure going to
change
that you're seeing it's hard to say man
there's
no one really no one really knows what's
going on right now
as far as education um
[Music]
so i don't know it's hard to say it's
crazy it could it could change education
forever or
a couple more months are going to go by
and everything's going to go back to
normal
it's a it's hard to say i don't i feel
like it's not
i mean i don't know what the hell it's
get what it looks like but to me
like going back to normal just seems
like it's not going to happen
i don't know i i know i i hate to think
that but
it crosses your mind i just think that
it's
so for me i just think that there's so
many things that
the the coronavirus and the quarantine
and like this whole thing like pointed
out that's like
we knew it was bad but it's like
pointing out
you know as we as we grow with
technology even as we grow
as just like a civilization and humanity
and we get smarter it's like
you got to be updating the books that
the kids are eating and what they're
teaching and why you're teaching it to
them and
yeah you know a lot of our school system
is based off of like let's get some
factory workers ready to go
and that's not the world we live in like
factory workers is like the last thing
you want to be
being trained for um and again i'm not
in like i haven't been
involved in any sort of school in the
last 10 years so like it could have been
[__] changing drastically for all i
know
i don't know it just seems like we're
going to have like the stuff that
that you and i learned when we were back
in school it seems like
if i was a kid i would want to know way
different stuff like i would want to
know way more about the world and not
just like
the you know what happened in american
history
so i don't know but
there is a difference like it's cool to
have a bunch of teachers on zoom and
stuff and teaching in that way like
it'd be cool to see kids being able to
like learn what they really want like if
you know you're
you're 13 and you love uh
music production you know like if you
could be able to like get matched up
with like a great music producer teacher
even if there's not one in your town
like you you take a zoom class online
and that's like your schooling or
something but
that'd be cool but there's a lot that
you miss out when it's on
but it's also going to cost money
yeah that's what it doesn't in public
schools
public schools are cheap free
what a what a weird
we're up against change for sure man
i'm just kind of curious like how it's
gonna
how it's gonna go down next all right
play with me that that [__] is crazy
different like school starts next year
and it's so different it's
unrecognizable fantasize with me
what do you think it would look like
what would be the best case scenario
the best case scenario like let's say we
get like cash flow
money too like we could just the the
government has just
supplied like all right we need to put
all of our money into schools in this
situation
what would it look like like how can we
best teach the kids
like are you saying if like we had all
the money to
make education the way we think it
should be yeah let's do that
oh man well
i would go monday through thursday for
sure four days
for sure work week should be like that
too yeah
um i just think that's
five days is a lot for 14
or six through 18 year old
like it's a grind yeah
and like mental illness is just getting
worse
year by year there's some like
kids these days have so much so much
[__] going on in their lives
not that we didn't either but it's just
a whole different
like with social media like it's
negativities in their face every single
day
right like no matter how positive their
life is
like they're watching negativity on a
daily basis
and that subconsciously starts to just
mess with your
your mindset 100 and so
uh i think kids get burnt out
mentally and physically and emotionally
like like
do they need to go to school five days a
week
is it is it gonna is it gonna hurt them
at all
if anything they're getting more
retention because they're getting more
sleep
hopefully if they take advantage of the
extra day right
but yeah i don't know i would do that
for sure though
yeah and i feel like i feel like it also
will would boost um
it would boost your staff and how they
how they work productivity i feel like
it would boost it
because they're getting an extra day too
to prepare or rest or
reset the brain and
education is tough man dude for real i
guess
it's tough like people get burnt out too
adults do so um i feel like
everyone would it's a win-win i feel
like everyone would benefit from a
four-day week
i think that's a solid idea i've seen
that idea like i'm saying for work
too i've seen um you know like reddit
just the titles on reddit like every
couple weeks is like should we go to a
four-day work week or like it's a
four-day work week coming
and it would obviously trickle over into
schooling so
we forget that you know where
when you're learning like when you're
consuming like you're taking stuff in
it's not always just like instant like
your brain your subconscious mind is
always like working in the background
for you it's putting together some stuff
like
you to have the sleep to even be able to
like comprehend for sure you know it's
that's how our bodies work we've got to
be able to like sit on some stuff and
change our views of it or um you know
you can't just like
all right here's the thing you're going
to learn and i'm going to shove it into
your brain as hard as i can for an hour
and then you know it you know it's rest
and recovery is when we learn it's just
like with muscles man like you go
you go to the gym and you tear it up and
then when you're healing this that scar
tissue like reheals right yeah you know
that's how you get big
yeah for sure
i think that uh i don't know to me
it it's very interesting to see how
the the zoom calls and facetime and uh
like for me like uh my my counselor like
i went
i started doing uh facetime calls for
that
it and it was it wasn't as good at all
um but it was like okay that is way
better than just nothing for sure like
being able to have that facetime
conversation
or just walk around your phone whatever
yeah um i'm wondering if like we'll
we'll improve it like we'll take the
good things like okay this is nice to be
able to
like have kids in their own safe
environment um
but still be able to learn um but i'm
kind of wondering if maybe like as our
technology advances if we can have some
sort of
because there's still this this and
everybody feels it like when you're
it's just of course not the same as
being in person like if i was trying to
do the podcast like just
through zoom calls it's it's not as
smooth you know
you gotta have you gotta have that human
interaction you know that biology in the
air
right bouncing back and forth well and
you're able to like when you're talking
to
even as a counselor like we were able to
talk to a kid and you know you know like
put your hand on his shoulder and you
like
be frank with him look him in the eye
and be like come on man or no
there's a lot of power in that like with
words we're trying to communicate how we
feel
there's definitely a presence you feel
in person other than on a phone
yeah for sure yeah do you feel like your
um your your upbringing
did you always plan on being a counselor
like since you were young like what was
your
where was your head at when you were
back in school yourself i didn't
i didn't think about being a counselor
until i was at central
yeah yeah um
yeah it was a late decision yeah
would it what have you it'd be hard to
summarize i'm sure but like what are
some things that you've learned from it
or like what's a
what's a big takeaway like thus far um
it's been a couple years now as far as
being a counselor yeah
someone always needs you oh there you go
someone always needs a person to fall to
fall back on
um and it's not always going to be
the person they're closest to
so like for a kid it's not always going
to be the kid's parent it's not always
going to be the kid's guardian
it's not always going to be the kid's
best friend it's
it's gonna be it could be anybody and
as a school counselor a lot of times
that's you
that's pretty real because i feel like i
100 wouldn't have
i don't know if i super opened up to my
school counselors but there's like
i would definitely be willing to tell
someone who like is in that position
over
somebody in my family or somebody close
to me right it's crazy it goes back to
that facade we're always trying to keep
up right
we don't want them to to think that
we're weak we've got some [__] going on
at home yeah
like you want to be the tough yeah yeah
that that was my problem growing up
i like as you've talked
about your life too like we both hid
so much about our life like we wanted
we didn't want anyone to know like what
it what it really was
right and i feel like i feel like i was
super misunderstood growing up
yeah yeah in a lot of ways
because i always acted like i had it all
figured out and i was acting like i had
it
i had a had a good and i got away with
it because i was a good athlete
so yeah
i i catered to that and used that to
to make people think that i was good
right see i mean i did my similar things
in so many ways like i
i was just talking about um just just as
an example like
at the end of my work shifts i would um
like you know it's like nine o'clock at
night or whatever and
your manager whoever was like working
with you like all right you good like
you need a ride and you know you walk
outside cause you have a car or whatever
oh yeah my ride's murdered down the
street just got off the phone with my
sister she's on the way
oh so many times and then as soon as you
see those taillights all right let's get
walking got a couple miles to cover yeah
or you get dropped off a couple houses
down like this is me
right right my homie dev was just
talking about that he
he was saying like uh i think his dad
had like a van and he was like in a van
and
uh in it he had a van he was in a band
and so he had the same like just a
natural like
don't drop me off in front of the house
yeah sort of thing yeah isn't that wild
yeah it is and it's it's funny because i
look back and
like i'm not embarrassed one bit of my
upbringing
like i didn't have much it was a
struggle
like i went through so much [__]
but looking back i i'm thankful
like if i didn't struggle growing up i
wouldn't
wouldn't have got thrown wouldn't have
got through anything i've gotten through
in my life
see me like
i don't know man i'm i'm
like growing up like i had a great i had
a great childhood
on one hand yeah but out of
my childhood was also a struggle
um like growing up with a single mom
um being african-american
being raised in a predominantly white
town
being raised by a white family
you know there was a there was a lot of
confusion when i was growing up
there was a lot of confusion because
i'm i'm brown skin and
everywhere i look there's no one that
looks like me
you already felt like in like a
non-belonging right
um like i i swore i was adopted until i
was like five
you guys gotta tell me yeah i was like
so funny it's [__] up but
i i was literally like till i was like
five i was like
i was like the same the same really my
family there's no way
what are they gonna tell me yeah yeah
that's so messed up looking back but
yeah yeah oh yeah i was i was i was just
i was confused like
literally like my whole family is white
like family reunions of 100 and there's
one
colored person there and it's me did you
feel like
that was like was it an
obvious thing to people other than you
like was it
um like would people treat you
differently because it would people want
to bring it up would people address it
or what was it well i guess that's what
i should clear up
this i wasn't meaning any in any way
like i was loved to death
yeah everyone in my family i just want
to make that clear real quick no doubt
but
um i definitely felt different
yeah like even though i was loved like
and you know in a sense it was like i
was being overloved because that was
different
they're trying to like people are trying
to compensate because they didn't want
me to feel different
which it was there was nothing wrong
with that but uh but it was like it's
something you noticed
yeah it's literally i mean they're just
trying to make sure you're feeling that
level right but it's because they're
family yeah but
you know i feel like when you're a smart
kid because i always knew so in mine
um i don't know if this is super similar
but for me
like i you know at a certain age i
realized that i was the poor kid
and like i was hanging out with the kids
who like like
like everybody else's parents would
always give me the ride home
like um like i didn't have my own money
so they would like other parents would
cover
my my share of it you know and like they
it was all love and like that's so great
and of course they did that and they
took care of me and like all my friends
as parents and stuff
yeah um but like there was a point
you know where i for sure like noticed
that yeah and then you start to
um you know i have like i i've been
kind of working through this with my
counselor i actually have um
like like when i was younger i started
to like notice that sort of stuff
i started to notice that my like
essentially i kind of started to pick up
would these people be friends with me if
they didn't know that i was like the
poor kid
like if they're p are the parents making
them hang out with me right like and you
know that's a very insecure like scary
place to put yourself
as a kid but that's kind of how i
started to form and like it affects my
relationship still to this day like i
gotta like
remind myself like this [__]
loves me and that's my homie man come on
what are you thinking about like they're
not
they're not hanging out with you just
because they have to what are you like
look around you know
but it's it's stuff that pops up you
know that's that's what you convince
yourself when you're
yeah when you're younger did you have um
do you have anything like
like similar like that that you had to
kind of look back on and like re
reassess in that same thing when it
comes to like the color your skin
um i don't know
like you just kind of like came to terms
with it i guess as you got older
yeah i mean i mean i i dealt with racism
growing up
but after a while
because back then there was really like
four four or five of us
like that the african-american community
has grown a lot
now but when i was in elementary school
i i probably couldn't tell you if there
was four or five right
so it was a lot different and
it was it was something i just came to
terms with
like people are gonna say what they're
gonna say like
is it worth my time to get in a fight
every day right
or no no or do i just let it roll off
i'm a kid what am i gonna what change am
i gonna make
you know so do i let do i let these kids
break me down every day or do i just
let it go and that's
and that's how it ended up being until
now
um i just had that mindset and that
that reaction to my whole life so it
just kind of grew with me
um yeah i don't know
like we the last time we talked we
talked about giving things power
yeah you give things power yeah and so
people just wanted reaction so
there's no power in what they're saying
until you give them that reaction
like if you just ignore them and say
like you feel better like
they're going to fill them away and
they're going to like feel weird and
they're gonna shut the [__] up
right so that's what i always did
that's kind of i never i never gave
anyone power behind their words
i never gave them the reaction they were
looking for you let them take your power
at the end of the day they just they
want to see your reaction they want to
see you hurt
but if you show them you ain't hurt
because you don't give a [__] what they
got to say
then they're not getting what they want
right
and eventually they stop saying it yeah
it's it's literally like you
i don't know i guess in that situation
it just seems like it's like you're
clearly the
the one who's more intelligible about
like like
someone could say all these things about
you and i just imagine you just like
all right you're just standing there
like so what's up like
and well i i just used to be straight up
i said
do you feel better now do you feel
better and they never have anything to
say
dude that probably frustrates people
yeah choking over their words
because who how do you how do you
respond to that it's like the
greatest rebuttal like i i'm not
interacting with your [__] man yeah
it's dumb and it's not that's not even
like a comeback ideas for a race that's
any kind of [__] i get like i just
like anyone's just being an [__] to
say
do you feel better yeah
okay move on let's go i love that [__]
dude
i like that because i feel like it stops
the we can get so much
momentum of like you're this and you're
that and we get you know social media is
a good example of that right we're just
always we're fighting these like
super zoomed in arguments versus super
zoomed in arguments of other people's
opinion but then when you zoom out it's
like
what are you talking about you're just
yelling like what are you
what are you yelling yeah those sort of
things halftime people don't even know
i know but when you call them out or you
or you like say like
how do you feel better yeah it stops
them in their tracks
and they think about what what they're
actually doing right
now like maybe i don't actually care
maybe i should chill
yeah it's wow man
that's wild well okay so while we're
right here
it's inevitable that what's going on in
the world
this would lead right into so
i wanted to we talked a little bit
before this like i feel like every time
i stumble upon
like just the the craziness that's going
around in the world right now
with race um
i want to be clear like i don't
i just feel like i don't really have
like an important voice about this like
it's not really my place to say
um but i do like i mean you you grew up
in this town and you had to deal with
it's you know some form of racism right
and um
you know i would hope that we've grown
since then but
you know in case we haven't um
i don't know i just i i guess i i
wouldn't want you to like be like you
need to represent
to represent all black people i'm
telling them one person one voice
right i just um i guess i guess what i
want to say mac is like
um is there a way that like
me as your white friend like is there a
way that we can have a conversation
or do we need to have a conversation
like can we help out people in this area
by like saying a certain thing like is
there things that
like i'm arrogant about that i don't
know about um
i i i don't know again i don't want you
to feel like you need to like represent
or like have a
huge say on it but i guess without
saying what's your hot take on what's
going on right now like what
what do you think man like how can we
help one another like get because
this [__] is crazy to me yeah and i like
we need to we need to figure out what to
do next like if there's issues we got to
solve them and we got to figure out we
got to make them better 100
yeah but i think that descending into
madness isn't the way so
i'm for sure you know i think i think
the biggest thing
is just like holding yourself
accountable
like being the best you can be
personally
and then calling [__] out when you
see it
i feel like if everyone does that then
it weeds weeds the [__] out simple
yeah
it's it's as simple as that i mean at
the end of the day you can only control
what you can do
so as long as everyone just worries
about themselves and their own morals
and their own actions and then
when they do see [__] just call it out
it's important i think that
there's been this weird like if you
aren't with us you're against us kind of
kind of vibe with a lot of um
i don't know i guess social media is
just such a [__] it's put such a shitty
thing in our heads with with
so much of what's going on um i feel
like
we're so so even me for example again
like i know i have a podcast and i want
to try to be like a positive person and
try to
you know like help people out and
inspire people whatever way i can so
like when this started happening i
i was like dude i need to like do i need
to say something do i need to see if i
can help people like do i need to blah
blah
and then i i was just like what why
would i
like i ain't got my voices shouldn't be
heard right now like that's not what's
important
um but i i think that a lot of us think
that we need to like do so
much like we need to fight this and we
need to
um i don't know i guess
emphasizing what you just said of like
concentrate on what's in front of you
like like fix yourself like notice what
you're saying notice what you're doing
um i think i was listening to to eric
weinstein who's like a mathematician he
has a podcast
um and he had he had his his friend on
and they were talking about like he was
kind of angry at the beginning of the
podcast he was basically like
we haven't had the conversation about
race because like we we it's my friend
he comes over and we start talking about
the [__] that we like
like you don't really stop and think
about it um but
but after he had said that it's like oh
okay of course like i haven't ever had
this like
conversation in depth with with mikayle
or or my other friends
who are black like because
it's it's
i hate how uncomfortable the
conversation
gets like i hate how we feel like we
need to have like this weird
conversation but it's because
other people are putting words in our
mouths like when you have like just down
to your level
of like this is your homie bro we love
each other like if there's something
there that needs to be said like
what like if i was uh cracking
inappropriate jokes that i thought was
cool because we always grew up
as homies and we were always cracking
those jokes like i would want to be like
oh okay
maybe that isn't right like maybe that
is like kind of making him feel
uncomfortable he's laughing it off
like those sort of things we could check
ourselves
but you know other than that we can't we
can't go charge against the whole world
as
you know one individual and trying to
think that we need to break everything
as long as long as you worry about
yourself and your circle mm-hmm
it'll it'll benefit everyone else's
circle
i mean that's that's the jordan peterson
way anyway man i mean
yeah i mean this whole world is just
different
different circles different clicks so if
you work on yourself
that improves your circle and the people
in it
and if they do the same they don't you
know people trickle into each other's
circle
ripples man yeah ripples for sure well
um i mean i just i wanted to make sure
that we like talk about it i'm just i'm
stating it and
just it feels weird for me because again
like it's just like
you're my homie and it's you're you
don't have a racist bone in your body
that's why it's uncomfortable
yeah you have you have this this
unwanted and un unneeded guilt that
you don't deserve right because you're
you're not that person
but you feel that way because people
of your descent are showing those
actions so you feel guilty because of
that
and that's a weird [__] thing that
now social media in the news like
is forcing upon us and is able to like
put in our heads so like i'm
i sit here and i'm getting all confused
i'm like like wait do i need to check
myself like what the [__]
but it's the media
dude it makes us crazy like it it
[__]
i think that it's important to be
fighting oppression
and fighting like you know there's very
real like there's
just to point out like there's very
[__] there is racist cops there's
racist white people there's
there's still racism it's there um but i
don't think that
i don't know i feel like if you just
look at your circle around you
like that's all you gotta worry about
you know that's
um i don't know man
it's awkward it's weird i hate how i
hate how it's awkward but i hope that
like maybe just talking about it makes
it less awkward next time or something
yeah but you're my homie mom
yeah all right bro what do you think's
gonna happen with all like
with the craziness of the world like not
not just the race stuff
but you know we got coronavirus we've
got
uh everything shut down like the economy
is [__] weird
we've got mental health we've got like
people losing their goddamn minds
is the world descending into chaos are
aliens gonna be the next thing
we're just gonna come break this up the
the
the craziest thing about all this
is that like this is the craziest the
world like if you really think about it
this world is going bonkers
and keeping that in mind like
everyone's like chilling like no one's
no one's truly freaking out because our
our generation's been through so much in
our lifetime like
it's like it is what it is but if you
think about it like
everyone like in theory everyone should
probably be freaking out because this
world's going
to right it's literally going up in
flames yeah all signs are pointing to
weirdness
yeah but everyone's chilling like that's
just our society now like
we're we're we see so much negativity
on social media and so much like graphic
[__] every day like so we're like this
isn't phaseless
i feel like but it probably is dangerous
though that's what i mean i feel like
[__] man like should we be paying way
more attention than we are
right i mean we have been like yeah yeah
we have been like so numbed to
the madness of the world you know
we see if you look at if
if you look at like what the what the
news tells us you know we
it's i i like to you know social media
and news media
is very different than when it first
started out
like uh i mean social media i guess
maybe not but like if you think about
back in the day when they first had tvs
and like our great grandparents or
grandparents even were watching tv and
[__] it was like
what you watch is the truth like this is
what you're like the leader of your
country he's gonna
you know if he comes on the news and he
has something to say that's what you
listen to and that's the truth but now
it's like
there's we we realize years and years
later we realize that social media and
the news media it's just corporations
man
they're just trying to get you to stay
on their site they're just trying to
like
get the clicks get the time on their
site um and by doing that they're
[__]
they're gonna they're gonna crank up
your amygdala man they're gonna get you
angry they're gonna get you fearful if
it's all just
love and chill and it's just pictures of
of sunsets on social media like they
don't get as many people
on their platform and so it's like this
battle for everybody's attention
but i think that we've like we've
maximized that in so many ways and like
you know now we have ai algorithms that
are like feeding us exactly what we want
to know
it's feeding us like if you kind of
believe this
it's going to suggest you some other
stuff that will really make you believe
that because that's going to keep you on
their platform longer
dude i think i listen to this thing uh
from sam harris
and he basically had like a two hour
long basically kind of pointing out like
a lot of the statistics
of just the craziness that's going on
and
essentially pointing out that like we're
kind of we kind of are like losing our
minds in in a strange sense
um you know and i think it's because of
like social media
in the news and i don't think we're i
don't think a lot of us are aware of how
much this affects us and how much we're
constantly thinking about
stuff that's not actually like in our
lives around us in physical reality
right right [__] here
and man i i hope i find myself
um like just with
talking about all these things i find
myself almost getting like mad
man like like actual anger of like what
the [__] man like what
what i think about young kids right now
growing up like jesus man these poor
hopeless kids
probably because you know all their
leaders
all of the people in charge like it's
just a known thing everybody's corrupt
that's just how we do it
like kids tune into tv and they watch
their president
which you know the president has always
been someone we're supposed to be
inspired by and
and want to like actionalize
we want to like look up to the person
the leader you know and there's not that
like you pretty much
know that everybody who's taking care of
you doesn't really care for your best
interest now
it'd be hard to be hopeful as a young
kid right now man it kind of just makes
me mad at i
and who i'm mad at is like the
the news media and like whoever the
[__] puppeteer is that's controlling
whatever the hell is going on right now
like
it's just [__] man it's it's crazy
that's crazy returning i feel like
there's the the mental health steps is
continuing to grow
it's gonna it's gonna continue to get
worse i mean
but the gdp is rising bro yeah yeah
don't you understand
the best it's ever been i i'm i am not a
parent obviously but
i feel like it's more it's more
difficult
and i said this in an interview a couple
months ago um tdn they interviewed a
couple counselors
um but i feel like today
is harder to raise a child than i was in
the 80s or 70s
because back then you know there's a
couple
tv channels you know
so like your your influence
was slim like your influence was
whatever those three
those three channels were so
like everyone's watching the brady bunch
it's okay all these kids growing up okay
this is how you act
so the morals were more controlled
the the influence is more controlled and
nowadays kids can get influence from
millions millions of different outlets
negative or positive
and parents don't really have control
of what those influences are unless you
literally just
take away all social media but i mean
that's going to cause
problems on its own because they're left
out and they don't fit in because
they don't have a cell phone and every
one of their friends do
how many kids didn't have social media
when you like when you were teaching
is it pretty much all kids in high
school have social media 100
percent no 98 right
and it is super weird to think that like
there's people who
like rich businessmen who are just doing
the money thing really well
they're the ones who are influencing
your kids more than you
like that's [__] crazy that's
i mean but i wouldn't know what to do i
mean here's the thing is like
i have my own addictions towards social
media if i had a if i had a kid
i would you know maybe i'm i'm sitting
there on right next to him on the couch
on my own social media
absolutely you know i think that we um
i posted this thing yesterday that was
mostly nonsensical but what i was
basically saying is like
technology you know we've always grown
like
so humans like okay think of humans like
right after apes man like we started
using
you started using tools like whatever
your belief is how this happened we
started using tools
and then we started communicating with
each other started just
you know civilization is able to grow
because our ability to use these tools
but every time we
learn about a new tool we get like a
let's call it a psychotechnology
which is just like the human's brain the
human brain's ability to to operate that
tool and remember
what it does and then build upon that so
like we made the wheel for pottery
um i mean i don't know how many years it
was in between but eventually it's like
oh
flip that up and it's a wheel you know
and you could do a lot a lot with that
you can start um
you don't know how the hell went but you
know eventually years and years you can
get a car
out of the wheel yeah and we get psycho
technologies along the way
we get the ability to understand these
things
more and more um and it's just
inevitable like so now think about
human beings when the wheel first came
around like a newborn baby
like the amount of information they
would have to know let's say
ages zero through five like you pretty
much gotta learn how to
survive and you know work that wheel
or whatever the technology is at that
time but now it's like
kids are are smart like they know they
know so much
information of psycho technology so much
in
so many ways to use different kinds of
tools and different technologies
um and i i think that if we look at you
know the human consciousness
it's inevitable it's no doubt that we're
like changing and adapting and
you know evolution that's how it works
right
i just think that what i was pointing
out in the post is kind of
that we don't really realize how much
we're changing
like with the technology until it's like
a few years afterwards and like you can
look back like
wow that changed our culture a lot like
you you know there was probably
10 15 20 30 years of like when cars were
first starting to come out and start to
actually like to where
you know people were starting to see
them where
the people would realize like oh our
life is way different like
before the cars i would have been just
working on the farm all day
and i never would have been able to
drive to this next town or whatever we
start just expanding and society
connects um i think that
for me someone who you know my age you
were you were one year under me
but my age i always say we're riding the
wave of technology of social media like
it was just we definitely agree with it
yeah it was just enough to be just
cool as [__] we were right at the nice
edge and there wasn't a ti
i don't think there was like a crazy
amount of like competition so it wasn't
like
you know it's like you get what what the
popular thing is like now you're going
to get an iphone back for us it was the
razor man
it's like oh [__] like and you don't
think about the bad repercussions of the
razor
you're just like bro my [__] is slim as
all hell yeah look at this phone i can
just put it where when whatever pocket i
want click
yeah goodbye and you hang it up i kind
of missed being able to just do it
that's my pink razor how would it be
so many people had a pink ring i don't
know that was a thing with my pink
shoelaces but i guess what i'm saying is
like
we me looking back in retrospect like i
love social media i loved
all the crazy cool [__] that like
technology and all that you know myspace
msn messenger it was so cool but like we
don't really think of like i wonder how
that like
changed my consciousness i wonder how
that changed my personality how that
changed what i do every day how it
changed my habits how it changed
my interactions with other people
and i can look back now and say it 100
did
i think that i lost a lot of like my
social interactive ability just because
like when i was working out warehousing
for five years i would literally be on
my phone for like 10 hours
just you know if the machine's running
good if you're doing everything right
you're [__] just
side glancing at your phone i think that
it like hurt my ability to have like
eye contact and great communication yeah
um
and i i just i just wonder if we're
we've changed so much our psycho
technology has changed so much
that we're like almost able to not
really see that we're like
losing our minds like we have changed so
much along with it that we haven't been
able to stop and be like
are we going in the right direction are
we like why are we changing with this
why is it that we want these things like
why do we have social media does it
benefit our life
do we just have it because everybody has
it do we what do we think about it do we
think that
you know we were talking about how we
have to be a chameleon all the time and
we have to change who we are like in
certain certain aspects
a social media is kind of this weird
thing that that makes the
societal part of our brains or the the
you know
the self that we identify with we're
always reconnecting like we're oh we
know we're this
we're reconnecting to that one thing and
like what if that ain't really you like
what if
when you were 16 you made your social
media and you're like i'm the [__]
cat guy
yeah i love cats and you're the
underscore cat underscored guy
and then like you know when you're 20
you're like i don't [__] care about
cats but like this is
this is my whole personality now i just
made it and i'm just coming back to it
so i don't know man i think that i just
want to point out that
we need to be aware of how these things
are changing us
and um just take a look at it man i
think it's making us lose our [__]
minds
yeah it might certainly might be it's
it's crazy to think about
like where this all goes yeah because if
you think
10 years ago [__] five years ago
we're all thinking there's no way
anything's getting crazier than this
like there's no way they're gonna make a
better iphone than this there's no way
they're gonna make a better tv than this
like this is it for technology right and
every single year it just continues
so it's like where does this go well and
think about how recycled we are too we
you look at an old tv if you look at a
tv that came out six years ago you're
like that's like the picture isn't very
yeah so played out like our brains are
like
our psycho technology is literally
getting better where it's like 4k
is a good tv yeah like you don't put
that big old tube tv in front of you
that's terrible exactly and it's and
it's funny because like
the the best comparison is like watching
like a
old sports game from like the 90s
and it's like damn like we really used
to think like
this was like picture perfect like we
used to think that this quality was like
because it was the best at the time
right like that was the best we've ever
seen
and then you go back it's like how did
we even watch that like i can't even see
the tv
well even at the beginning we didn't
even care that it was shitty it was just
like you could watch that and you're not
vaping because we didn't know
it was shitty right dude it's like the
more knowledge we get it's almost like
it inevitably comes with the bad you
know it always comes with the bad
yeah it's it's it's crazy to
think where technology will go what are
we worried because you know you know
it's going to keep growing
dude i history has proved that so
well and it grows at a uh moore's life
it grows at a rate where it just keeps
like doubling and it's
it's faster and faster and the i mean uh
have you
have you heard of neural link um elon
musk's
like uh like the chip that goes in your
brain no so
it sounds like something i don't want
dude it's
so it's crazy i heard about uh bill
gates trying to do something like that
oh yeah see with his 5g towers yeah he's
causing the coronavirus
that's all that uh conspiracy theory
[__] well so so the thing with um
the thing with neuralink and elon musk
so he was uh like
less than a month ago or so he was on
joe rogan again and he basically
announced
or like kind of told joe like where
they're at with neuralink
and neuralink is gonna be a microchip
that will go into your brain
and it's uh it's like obviously it's not
forced like not everybody has to do it
but
they peel back a part of your skull and
they
it's essentially like it's like
uncorking like a little part
of your actual skull itself and then
they put the chip in there and then and
then it just smooths back over
so it'll be like a flush thing and what
it's able to do man it reminds me of
like neo in the [__] matrix
it uh it essentially he literally said
it's within a year it'll be like in the
first human for sure
and they're they're you're literally
able to repair
neural pathways in a sense of like if
you're blind it'll make you see again
if you're paraplegic if you can't
control your legs
it will reform the connections that you
need and start rebuilding and you could
[__] use your legs again
he's going to start building superhumans
superhumans dude and he said in the the
weird thing is
it said you'll actually be better than
you were
in a sense like after like it's not like
an immediate like you can all of a
sudden just like walk on the walls or
anything but
um it repairs the thing that can repair
the things
so like your eyesight if you have
deterioration of eyesight like
it rebuilds your cornea and stuff like
your eyesight would be better than it
was before that's crazy
and that's what dude he was saying that
within a year it's going to be in the
first human
it's just wild i think that we're uh
i mean i don't know where elon calls us
organic boot loaders for ai
and it just kind of creeps me out but i
don't know
yeah man yeah that's a true
technology has taken us for a rip i i'm
glad that i love technology
and i think it's all fascinating i love
like learning about it i mean now
music music-wise you're able to there's
people who uh
like plug uh like a transmitter into
like leafs and plants and we're able to
like play
the sound that that plant makes through
speakers now because plants make an
individual like
they admit a frequency yeah what the
[__] where it's crazy
it's so sick i'm excited for it but i
think it's important to take a look and
like realize where we're at right like
instead of just being on social media
like make sure you ask yourself like
wait hold up
why am i on here like what am i gaining
from this what is this giving me
you know where nothing nothing
i it's i feel like it's more of like a
job to me now like i i don't i'm not on
it nearly as much i don't like it i
actually wish that i didn't have it
but i feel the need to like i think we
all do deep down
right i don't i don't think any of us
truly
want it but we're just so addicted to it
yeah
or just sleeps do it it's just like
i don't know that's just my perspective
i don't know that because i don't
i don't think for other people but
that's my perspective
yeah i think that if you told me that
five years ago i'd be like bro i love
like i would just explain to you
this in-depth thing of like why social
media is good for me
then i don't realize that i'm like as
people are trying to talk to me i'm like
oh yeah uh-huh and i'm
glancing at my phone right like what the
heck man like be present and get here
it takes away a lot from us it teaches
us a crazy ton but
we just gotta notice it we gotta realize
that it's changing us
for sure maybe yeah he's gonna sprout up
out of the ground
maybe that's the aliens oh man did we
did you say we talked about aliens last
night yeah we did
try to lead us into it again i don't
remember what we're saying i'm trying to
sound like
like just sound like a couple of mad men
predicting their future with aliens
yeah man it it's
it's hard to say it ain't coming i'll
tell you that
i mean the cia didn't they like submit
documents that like said like yeah we
saw it or
they they don't dispute it rather
at this point in life i am
not doubting anything
i'm i'm convinced that um
whoever needs to will hide
anything so if it's out there
they're hiding it right then i'm no
longer doubting that
probably been out there for a long time
too facts yeah
there's a reason you can't go anywhere
near area 51.
yeah dude we were talking about that
think about all the weird things that
happened and then we kind of forget
about them like area 51 like
like it was pretty much this like couple
months of
on social media anyway and read it and
whatever they're trying to get
militias together in russian right bro
well no but that's what i'm saying like
at first it was like hey this is real
and there's a lot of like uncovered and
there's like people on podcasts and
there's people who are like coming out
and saying like hey i worked on this
ship and blah blah blah
and then we're at this point in society
we're like that's not real is it
and then all of a sudden there's so many
people who are like dude that must be
real let's charge this place so it
it went it turned into like almost a
joke right but then it kind of trickled
out
and now we're not really talking about
kind of like just like the jeffrey
epstein thing just like well it's it's
crazy because
those people are literally told they'll
be shot down if they came anywhere near
it
so it's like what are they what are you
hiding right what are they hiding
but that's the thing is like is it is
us knowing us just like whatever
civilians with our level of intelligence
like is that really more important than
like like they might be
actually doing us a favor by not showing
us this crazy [__] right
right maybe we're slowly working up to
where our brains could even [__]
understand it like
if you show us a 4k tv back in 1964
you'd be like what the [__]
what the [__] bro thanks they they know
we're not ready for that
yeah whatever is down there damn
they know we ain't ready to see it it's
probably just lizard people bro
there's lizard people running the
government there's a lot of
there's a lot of conspiracy theories
that like uh
it's funny nowadays there's more you
know
things that would have been conspiracy
or labeled conspiracy
even 10 years ago are now like there's
like thousands and thousand thousand
people like actually having
conversations about them
um i think it's conspiracy that the name
was like
apparently even after jfk was killed
um like that whole fishy scenario they
basically like
anybody who was saying that it was
or trying to point it out or trying to
uncover whatever the government or the
fbi or whatever i don't know exactly
what i'm talking about but they said
um they're the ones who started they
actually inserted the word conspiracy
theory like they started
bringing that to the public and that
it's kind of a way to like anybody who
tries to whistleblow or tries to call us
out we just call them a craziness yeah
and there's a lot of people like even
conspiracy theories now who like
uh there's like uh
wait i don't even know if i want to say
his name because they're like taking
down his youtube [__]
there's a well i will david ike um i
don't i don't
follow him but he's essentially he's one
of the guys who's saying that like five
corona virus is caused by 5g
like i don't know [__] about that
that just seems like way too much
madness but
um like there
he's been saying that his whole life has
been writing books about like this [__]
like his whole life he's been an author
of like being the conspiracy theorist
guy
and it's so easy to write him off and
call him a crazy ass but
if you look at some of the things that
he says like mixed in throughout that
it's like it
has predicted and it has been true and
it has like whatever it kind of makes
you think you know
who's the one who's choosing to write
them off as a conspiracy theorist
we just anticipate the government we're
never being truthful to us but
mm-hmm it's [__] wild as well
life's wild life as well i think life is
about to get way more wild too for her
[__] civilization
not doubt it dude well i mean i think
we're gonna
we're gonna we're gonna get to mars for
sure
and i'm kind of just wondering if we're
you know because
our technology is getting good enough to
where like just dudes with enough money
are gonna start building more ships
um and they're able to like that we're
gonna start getting to places where
who owns space and whoever gets to the
let's say dark side of the moon
first they're able to mine it and
they're able to take those elements
and like all the all the [__] that we
don't know that's on the dark side of
the moon like maybe there's
uh an element there that's like would be
great for fuel
and we just haven't figured out how to
use it yet but like whoever has the most
money on the world right now is the one
who gets to do it it's gonna start a
world war
yeah and it's gonna the wealth gap is
gonna be real big what if there's gonna
be maybe we're gonna have like an
elysium sort of situation you ever seen
that movie
there's like a city in the sky yeah yeah
yeah
i think i've saw tv shows like that i
don't know
that particular one it was like matt
damon or something
i saw the 100. dude that's a tight show
actually like that
in stoke show that makes me think though
did you did you watch like all seasons
of it
yeah uh i didn't like the last season i
don't know about the word i don't know
if i watched the last season but i did
watch
like when they got to where there's like
the mountain people that that did make
me think of like uh
because there's been also like
conspiracies or myths or whatever of
like
there's a civilization towards the core
of earth or something
and that's some will [__] i'm not saying
i believe in it but it does make you
think like
i don't know man what if like you know
we just think our way
of of living in our way of civilization
is like the only way
and we think of like oh egyptians and
you know
like all these old civilizations as like
just
cranks like they're the conspiracy
theories they're the weirdos but like
they could be smarter than us in a lot
of ways they could know
levels of technology that we never
explored because we just assumed that
the whole area was just
man that's a weirdo we're not even going
to follow down you know
it's interesting to think yeah
how we feeling how you doing on time
i'm good i'm 123.
i ain't bad yeah all right bro what's
your plan for uh
summer like life's changing for you
what's your what's your projections
right now like what's
summer and afterwards like where's your
head at what are you thinking
i don't know i just made a big life
decision
and i'm happy with it yeah um
i don't think people should be afraid of
change
i feel like change can be a good thing
yeah and a positive thing
um so that's where i'm at man just
just gonna ride it out see what happens
and
enjoy it you're so easy going man you
gotta be
you are you gotta be do you equate it to
your to your mom like i know you and
your mom have a good relationship
yeah is she is she like that too like no
no no she'd be the first to tell you
no not at all um i don't know why i'm so
chill man
i really don't i think
i don't know i feel like part part of me
feels like i was forced to just
be a chill dude just given my
environment growing up
but part of me just doesn't know
like i've just always been super chill
yeah and
a lot of people take it as i i don't
care
but i'm really just chilling like
sincerely chilling yeah i'm 100 percent
fine yeah like i don't
i don't know how to explain it this is
who and that's
and that's what i was saying earlier
like i'm i feel like i'm so
misunderstood
i always have felt that way um
i don't know how to say it though do you
think out like race not being involved
at all like do you feel like you just
felt because me
like i feel like the way that i
perceived the world
was different like the way that like i
would i would have different
conversations than other people were
having or i would have
i would point out things that um like
other people weren't talking about or
something
and like a lot of like for me
i felt different because i could tell
after a while that like i perceived the
world differently than a lot of people
um and i'm sure everybody feels that way
in certain senses right
but i don't know i don't know for
for me where was i going with that
talking about how we perceived the world
i'm just thinking differently being
chill
i was asking about your mom's influence
um for for me as i feel like i was so
misunderstood because
my whole childhood i was
i was like a freak athlete
growing up and i hated it
i hated it so much because everyone
everyone assumed i was cocky and
arrogant because that comes with being
good at what you're doing and that that
was so not me
i hated the spotlight i hated it
because i because i knew people would
assume i was cocky
yeah and it was arrogant and i just like
when i was 12 i used to hit home runs
and like get pissed right after
like i was riding on the bases and i
wouldn't smile i'd go in the dugout i
wouldn't smile my teammates get pissed
because i'm not smiling
and it was like i wasn't putting on an
act like i was like
i didn't want it like obviously i'm
gonna do my best but every time i did i
was just like
pissed off because i was like well
people are gonna assume i'm cocky again
and so so many people
thought that way of me like all the way
through high school
and that just got your hockey back yeah
a lot a lot of people did
and as it was unfortunate because this
it wasn't me
like people saw like i feel like
a lot of people only saw me in that
light like i was the athlete
i was always smiling had friends
i think they didn't see the dark side
they didn't see the side of me that grew
up with a single mom
a lot of times it not power yeah i felt
a lot of
raised my sister for the most part
you know single mom she works a lot
right um
i was held at gunpoint at 10 years old
with a shotgun
um are you are you willing to talk about
that
or is that yeah i mean it was just it
was one of my mom's exes and
he broke into the house one night damn
man
held my sister and my mom gunpoint in
her room
that's crazy so i don't until this dad
don't know how but
i was sleeping on the couch in the
living room living room and he jumped
through the window
right next to and i was i slept through
it all
and somehow they got out of the room
because
he probably like froze up he was like
by like like rethinking a strap since
he's come too yeah so they got out
and then i woke up i wake up to this
dude
six four wake up two i'm ten years old i
wake up to him
standing like right in front of me on
the other side of the couch
and he goes don't worry i'm not here for
you
she's going for my mom and sister do you
see the gun you saw like yeah he was
holding them
12 gauge god damn and then
um so he gets arrested
and well before he because he ran so
before
he said i'll be back for you guys oh
that's [__] and so
he so he he gets arrested right and
does seven years so seven years go by
i'm 17. i'm a junior in high school
he gets out he comes back to town
my mom and sister flee to tacoma for two
weeks
i stayed at my best friend's house for
two weeks and didn't go to school
and he got arrested because he came back
to town
i did went back to prison so it's like
i was dealing with all that but no one
knew
because i don't want anyone to know
right i wanted to be normal
is that crazy yeah and then like
something so big in your life that's
like you know
you could probably use to talk about it
and work work through but we feel like
we don't have access to that
right and then um when i was 15 i lost
my
my grandfather and he was my father
figure
said and have a dad growing up and so
that's really that's really when life
changed for me
because i i was such a prude such an
innocent
for the most part actually i'll take
that back it wasn't that's not true
i had my phase in middle school but i i
really cleaned it up
until like my sophomore year yeah
because i got in high school and i
wanted to start taking things serious
i was getting pretty good at sports i
didn't want to mess up college
then once he passed away like well that
father figure was gone
and then i started dabbling again doing
whatever
didn't really care about much other than
just playing sports my academics dropped
all that all that
but ended up working out
i'm here oh yeah yeah and then i got
i got to college at central um
had no money okay so i i got to central
late
like i enrolled late and there's so few
jobs over there like
if you're not there in the summer like
you're not getting a job so
yeah yeah so i go there
because like it was my last year i
wasn't going to go back
i was like screw it i'm gonna start
working like i can't do this another
year
i hated the weather there couldn't stand
it
but i decided to go back and finish
and i went late so a job was out of the
picture
so i had no money so
instead of getting an apartment that i
couldn't afford
you sleeping car i would drive
i would commute every monday morning i
would
leave from kelso drive to owensburg
sleep on my car monday night tuesday
night drive back home wednesday
afternoon after class
skip thursday and friday class
and you made it through that like that
yeah just kept doing that
no it was a [__] do you feel like
that's like a
it's that you think it's that same thing
like we're talking about like you you
wait you say oh i got a ride coming
and you wait till they leave and then
you start walking that same thing like
is it oh 100
yeah oh thousand thousand percent
because no no one even knew what i was
doing
because i i had people i could have
stayed with but i didn't want to be that
person sleeping on the couch yeah
i had done that before i didn't want to
be a burden
dude why do we do that to ourselves
because like your homies would be happy
to have i mean but but i get it though
like i've been
like you know family growing up and
families are like you're not spending
christmas alone
you're going to our house and it's like
you know once they finally convince you
to or they whatever like you're at their
house
and it is great but there's also like
like
it's it's uncomfortable it's hard to
yeah no but i i am thankful though
because
um two of my friends allison delay and
danny eagleson
they they knew what was going on after a
while and they took me in a few nights
here and there but
i i refuse to stay there every night
and i was like i'm not gonna live on
your couch rent free like
i'll accept it like a couple times a
week but
i'm just gonna sleep in my car and do my
thing
i mean that's you know it's sad on one
level
like just you know inevitably like oh
you know it just bums me i think while
you sleep in your car really but
it's also like i feel like you probably
derive a lot of strength from that sort
of thing like being in 100 percent
you know you you can fall back on
yourself for sure like it's like i
i got me i know i'm gonna be okay after
the first
two weeks like the second week i was
there i
went to sleep and woke up with like five
six inches of snow
covering my car it was cold but
after after that it was more of a pride
thing
it was like i'm gonna prove to myself
that
i'll i'll really [__] drive here i'll
commute here
every week sleep in my car sit in the
rec center
from six in the morning till 11 pm until
it closes
and go back to my car watch a movie on
my laptop and go to bed
and do my [__] it was more of
a just i'ma do this for me i'm gonna
prove to myself that
life's not that hard right like this
sounds terrible but
like i'm i'm like i'm under at the end
of the day i have cover over my head
i got like i'm in a car yeah dude like i
could be
on the street without cover so
why would i [__] about this when
someone doesn't have a car to sleep on
and that's that's just the kind of
mindset i had to get through
and then you're able to you know teach
kids and and those same kids who are
going through you know younger but
similar situations
at home who like they you know they
don't want to talk to their friends
about it right like they don't want to
they don't want everybody to know
yeah that you can connect with them
that's like my biggest thing in life
like
just knowing no matter how how hard [__]
gets
like it always works out
and it's the weirdest thing like we
always getting put in these situations
like
how do i recover from this like how am i
going to get over this
and it you always you always do yeah
like look at your life right now like
however old you are right now
listening thank you you figured it out
every time yeah but like
think back in your life and how many
times you're like i'm gonna do this
like think about how many times in your
life like
you literally thought you could not do
something or you could not make it
through something
but you do every time it's just those
hours or those days in between
where like for whatever reason like you
have no hope
but it always works out and
we don't know how or why but it does
so it's funny to like think that think
about how much
like how much pressure we put on
ourselves
thinking that it's not going to get done
right but we know it's going to get done
like we're always going to figure it out
yeah like every paper i wrote in college
i was like
the [__] am i going to do this like i'm
a procrastinator i knew i was gonna
wait until three hours before it was due
and read a
five to ten page paper
i did that like almost every paper i
wrote because i just
if i know i had ten hours to me that
meant
i have another seven hours before i have
to start it yeah
because then i'll have three hours to do
it that's how i do a ton of people work
like that actually
and it's nuts like you have to have you
have to have to have some kind of
pressure on it to get it done
like if i have two days to do it why
would i do it when i have two days i
mean maybe you just knew yourself
like in in another level i mean like
what if
if you had a an apartment this whole
time like maybe you wouldn't be as
driven you know to go to class like
maybe you would but
maybe you kind of just like recognized
who you are and you know like i need
this to
to get this done i'm gonna do it this
way right
i think is i don't know
i don't know man i really don't there's
nothing like is it there's nothing in
your life that you're like man this is
like a defining moment where i was like
this is i'm gonna be chill
i'm gonna look at it optimistically like
this person taught me that it's just how
you are i
think life circumstance i think it was
just a build up
of everything i went through in my
childhood
yeah like
not only did i see my family at gunpoint
like i
witnessed my grandfather get shot up to
not killed but like because he was in
the house and he was getting shot up
and i was like eight damn man
so that shows do you remember like under
understanding it back then at all yeah
was it like later
it's it's crazy and they create the
i don't know why but the craziest thing
like my grandma still has the same
blinds
like there's still holes in them whoa
that's weird
but they're like 22 holes so that
they're like not like crazy noticeable
but how many times have you like looked
at those or zoom every time i'm here
every time i'm there that's wild you
think it's a you think it's a
like a bad thing like do you think like
you know her off of their place or is it
like i don't
i don't even know if she like notices
i think she's just like she's so like
she's so far removed from that
that she doesn't even like think about
it
or maybe she does it on purpose and she
just wants that reminder
like that's like like that's her way of
like having a part of him there
because they got there together did you
when you were younger
did you feel
for me when i was younger i felt
like i understood the adults
more than i understood the people around
me but also
there was a sense of i couldn't
understand why they're lying to me
about certain things like so for example
like uh
i don't really remember the situation at
all where i was way young i was under 10
years old but
my grandma passed away at our house and
i remember
what they were doing is they essentially
like you know family starts coming over
and
you know i'm sure like the police were
there or whatever afterwards um
but i remember like being upstairs
and there was like one of my cousins or
something that was trying to like
distract me and not get me to go
downstairs and trying to just like
um essentially i knew exactly what was
going on i'm like
grandma died it's going on downstairs i
can hear the adults crying
why are you lying to me and trying to
distract me like i didn't like that i
was
like being treated like a kid although i
was a kid right
um but to me like and it's it's a good
example like how i thought as a kid like
i felt like
i understood what was always going on i
just was
always the thing that i was confused
about was why
the adults around me were lying about it
trying to make me feel better
like they were doing great like they're
like of course you shouldn't just like
let your you know what seven-year-old
kid just hang out next to dead grandma
and
fill out the police report too jeez but
um
i remember feeling like i felt like less
trustful of the people around me because
i'm like why are you lying to me like
all right
it was a weird thing like where a lot of
kids i think would be better off
like just having that illusion whatever
but i always saw through the illusion i
just didn't like that i wasn't being
told about
it right i don't know did you ever feel
like you kind of knew what was going on
i always know what was going on yeah i
mean of course you did like dealing with
that [__] as such
i was i always understood adults more
than
my peers and
i think it's because i had to grow up so
fast at a young age yeah
like i always like i just always
understood adults
like their mindset was my
mindset like i had an adult mindset
rather than kids my age
see and i was always then that's like
all the way up until high school like i
always hung out with kids older
than me do you think that like your
homies who
were like around the similar age as you
like do you think they were probably
you know drawn to you in in those ways
because of that like uh
like you understand people
generally and such like you know a lot
of times when we're young we're just
focused on ourselves like we're just
wanting
we're just young you know but when you
see the people around you like
that everybody has needs and then
everybody has like an individual
perception of these things
you can like be more comfortable with
um the people around you it's like like
who wouldn't want to have someone who is
like
reasonable and understands the situation
and cares for everybody on an individual
like who would want to have that person
around so it probably like
drew you into relationships yeah i'm
sure for for me
and i think this is why i ultimately
ended up becoming a counselor
like growing up i was always
everyone's outlet
because i could always identify
everyone's pain
like i always saw through the [__]
like i
always thought i always saw through the
the facade
and i would always check in
like i would say like i know you're
struggling like what's up
like i know you're acting like you're
not but i put on that same facade yeah i
know bullshitter when i say a
bullshitter that's how i did like
how you doing for real yeah and i was
always like that
even as a kid yeah that's a valuable
that's a valuable place to be that's a
valuable friend to have around for sure
do you see that um in your counseling
job do you see that
in kids like do you see like oh this is
this is the this is the counselor
it's this 15 year old kid or is it
different
it's different i mean it's it's funny
because
it's funny because i'll see kids and
i'll see
younger versions of people in my life
and that's a [__] it's funny yeah
that's gotta be a trip
like not saying this happened but i'll
see a kid and i'll be like
damn that's jake that's that's 14 year
old jake right there
he's just wearing the tightest pants he
ever yeah his hair is pink
he's got eyeliner on yeah yeah black
nail polish
yeah wearing some etnies
hell yeah oh yeah we never last through
the skateboarding
yeah it's it's it's so funny how many
like phases i've went through we all
went through
oh man growing up especially me yeah i
mean because even
even i went through the at knees and
skater phase it's like
so many different it's hilarious for me
i feel like my
my faces were i mean even when i was
like way younger i really always liked
like
bright colors um i liked
i think that i was drawn to like the
being the rebel like i didn't so much as
want to be
um how do i phrase it
i wasn't trying to be different like i
was already inherently different
um but i i really felt like i i just
generally did like i just happened to
like the more like
exuberant [__] like i always liked like
i
i would see so skateboarder i would see
my favorite skateboarder wearing
something that was like
whoa that's so he's wearing like a
button-up leopard print
shirt and he's just shredding savage
yeah
and so i would be like i i don't know
because i never had anybody in my life
to like
say no we're like you're not supposed to
do that or like
that's a ridiculous shirt i don't know
so i would just be like of course
we have that freedom getting that yeah
so
um yeah it's so interesting to see how
we change over the years man like we
we do and we don't change and it's it's
a thing of beauty to realize that the
human being is such a
dance man we're not all we're not going
to get there we're not going to get to a
final form
like we're who we are throughout all
these things and we
and we change and we learn and we when
we get more information and we get
we get better and sometimes we get worse
yeah
that's uh it's a [__] thing of beauty
life
chameleons man chameleons
millionaire yeah i i think that
for me because i was kind of the
counselor too um
i was having uh after my podcast with i
think it was
taya sanders and then same with mac t we
were talking about
they brought up um like how natural this
situation is like the podcast and like
just
me you know trying to help people with
mental health and whatever dorky way i
can um
like they would be like oh of course
you're doing this and i'm like what like
what
i like i didn't plan on doing this i'm
not trying to like do this and just what
i feel that i should be doing right now
and they would talk about like they'd
bring up like me and mac t back in high
school dude we would just write
notes together i loved writing like so
we would just write like the longest
notes just pages and pages go back and
forth and we'd talk about like real [__]
like counselored to her and then same
with same with taya way back in the day
like she was a couple years younger than
us
and so she would come up to me for
advice like talk to me for advice and
all those long text talks and look back
like
oh yeah i guess you know as far as if
you had to choose who was the one
counselor for the friend group i guess i
kind of was that
like um but it's in that same way it's
it's an ability like because you can be
that chameleon and that's what you want
and you could be
you know um like
what people need like you can show up as
a version
of yourself like they already like you
but the version of yourself that's like
can really get to that part of them and
really allow them to like work [__] out
with you
um it's a for me i think that i that i
like with my depression and like like
you know in my
beginning of my 20s and stuff i feel
like
i was always so much of that that i
would like
i don't know that i like really it's
hard to say the words
i didn't know who i was but i don't know
i just feel like now at this age
i'm making more of my own decisions like
i have more like barriers
almost of like oh no i'm this like
i'm willing to to reshape myself and
i'll form to what what needs to happen
in the situation like i'll be this
version of myself like i
i don't have you know my pride isn't
worth getting in the way of like us
having this real talk like i'll
i'll get down i'll get to the level that
we need to be on but now more than ever
as i like learn more about like my mind
and emotions your studies definitely
you're more proud and understanding of
where you are in life
right and i've noticed that
like over the last year like you've
even made strides i'm proud of you for
that
thanks bro i appreciate that you can you
can just tell that
you're you're in a good place i am right
and you can tell that
you're you're finally comfortable and
you're happy with where you are
right you can see it i'm really trying
to be you know yeah
i'm trying to to figure out my own path
you know i'm trying to like learn as
much as i can and just
do what feels right i mean like uh like
i was talking about with dev yes uh two
days ago
like what if what if nobody ever
believed in themselves
like what if martin luther king just i
don't know i'm kind of a turd
i don't want to go up in there or what
if you know what if uh
elon musk is like no probably [__]
make [__]
any artist any musician like what have
they never believed in themselves
and i started to realize that i was like
not believing in myself like i don't
even know what i believe in myself
in but i know that like whatever i do i
got to do it because i'm the only one
who could do it
right like my my particular story just
like
everybody on this world like eight
billion people we've all got our own
story everyone
everyone's got something yeah you know
we've got
we've all got our [__] and we can only
step into it and for me
like i
p people-pleasing has been a big thing
that i've like trying to to dissolve
like because as a chameleon personality
it's also like
trying to make sure the vibe is always
perfect like it's uh
as much as when there's eight people
talking i notice
when there's someone trying to tell a
story and they kind of got overrun
and then the story kept going so i'm
looking right at them and i'm waiting
for the next chance so i can be like
anyway amy what were you saying like i'm
always
the same way yeah bro and i it's a
beautiful thing and i think it's a very
important role for any friend to have
and i love it and i wouldn't change it
but
i realized how often i was always in
that role i'm always like
who needs what in this room because i'm
gonna mold to that and after a while
because you know no one else is bringing
it right right and it's
it's important and it it is your
identity in a sense but for me it's more
of like
you know even as i get this podcast and
i start to like do my own research and
learn my own things like
sometimes i have i want to be able to
like stand up for myself and i want to
be able to be like
it's you know some things like i don't
know what i believe but there are some
things where i'm like
you know i think you're wrong i think
that i do believe that and
i don't think that me without like
practicing this and like talking to
people and trying to stand up for myself
like
i also see it as like if i continue to
do this and i continue to learn and feed
my brain and i continue to like
adapt and evolve just as a human and
really try to self-actualize and be the
best version of myself that i can in
whatever way that i can
i'm going to come up with people who
don't like that who don't like my ideas
and that's really uncomfortable for me i
don't like when people don't like me it
makes me super nervous i get
uncomfortable i start changing myself so
they like me because that's just how
i've
survived it's how i adapted and learned
the world around me yeah
it's like it's such a beautiful thing
but if you ain't noticing it if you
if you ain't like checking yourself in a
sense so i guess
over the last you know year two years
whatever like i'm just
learning more and i'm able to put up
more barriers and boundaries of like
i'm with you and i'm willing to like
dissolve myself and be ditto
in whatever situation i need to but
there is some things that i have like
values for sure is something that i have
now that i don't think that i had before
um just things that i like don't want to
sway on things that i'm willing to argue
for and
like willing to tell people that they're
wrong like that wasn't something that i
would never do before because i just
would avoid conflict in every way that i
can so
i i think if you're if you're honest and
sincere
about what you're doing
damn it's it's easy to not care
about someone's opinion like if they
ain't riding with you
whatever like you're you're being
yourself like yeah
can't beat yourself up about that but if
you're not being honest and you're not
being sincere about something you're
doing
right then then it's fair game for
someone to
judge you right and it comes across i
feel like it's like
you know the the feeling that we
inevitably get like people have been so
kind to me through like
you know just the podcast stuff people
are like willing to open up to me and
blah blah and i'm i'm sitting at the
other end of the table like hey man i'm
not trying to be anything i'm not i'm
not trying to say that i'm this i'm not
trying to say that i'm good at this
i'm just trying to like show up at the
level that i'm actually at
and i you know talk about the level that
you're actually at
and i think it's you know we can't ask
for much more than that man like none of
us [__]
i don't remember asking to be born do
you like i'm just trying to figure this
life [__] out i got dropped off man i
got dropped off the storks man there's
the aliens
yeah they came down they beamed me down
for sure
it's like dumbo yeah right
we're always just trying to figure it
out man and i think that when you could
just tell people you know like like the
race conversation like it's like
as far as a podcast goes like that's not
like the greatest content like just
hearing some like white dude fumble
around some like weird questions but i'm
not trying to not trying to say that i'm
a pro about this i just want to make
sure that it's you know addressed
because it's something that i feel is
important you know
in our society right now and i want to
make sure there's no like
um just you as like an individual you
know like i i'm looking out
for you so through the the
um that's like self-righteous like i did
this for you yeah
i'm sorry but no i just i think stomach
you know
i think a lot of people be surprised at
how
willing other people are to let you just
stumble through where you're at right
yeah
like i like like you know playing sports
or making art or singing like
dude people want to see you like your
friends just want to see you try even if
you're not the best singer
they just want to see you like i really
love playing football and i just
you know i know i'm not the best but
like your friends are like okay i never
thought of you to be the best i never
wanted you to be the best like you're
happy that's great for them yeah for the
for the most part people just want to
see
you succeed they want to see you happy
the genuine people yeah there's only a
select few that
wish wish on your downfall right
i i feel like the ratios
so much more positive than people think
right there's more there's more people
trying to uplift you than drag you down
and that's so true and but we have this
thing
i feel like especially with social media
has definitely amped it but we have this
thing where like
one wrong comment is just like we just
ignore every good comment like bro like
i'll get a hundred people saying like
thanks for what you're doing i
appreciate it blah blah and then one
person's like dude you're a turd
what are you talking about like and i'm
like i'm losing sleep
your shoes are untied bro your shoes are
entire
unprofessional piece of [__] it's in and
we we catch on to those things i mean
but more and more the more
i start to say uh my counselor told me
this thing
uh had been going on and on about this
that was just rambling you know
and she just goes uh like in a soft way
she just looks right at me she's like
and what's that tempting you to believe
she said that to me and i remember like
i literally laughed afterwards i was
like oh [__] i thought that i was
pointing it out like you're right you
know like and that's the same thing is
like
what people have to say about you
especially if they're wishing on your
downfall you know it ain't true
like it's it's like you could be like
okay like you you could think that
like you you you could you could try to
say that i'm that
but you know like uh that all that i'm
just saying that just goes back to the
power piece
like you give things don't give that
comment power right
and it won't bother you yeah at the end
of it at the end of the day there are
letters
on a cell phone god damn
don't give them power right won't bug
you
give power to the positive mm-hmm and
they're so much more positive
especially especially like when you're
like this
like the support that i get like people
are just so pumped about it
yeah like i just feel like like
grateful like so sometimes i'm like like
don't amp me up like i have this like
uh i guess almost like the spotlight
thing like i'm not trying to i'm not
trying to hit home runs here yeah
i'm not trying to like i'm go like i
guess that's what we're all shooting for
in a sense like you should be
shooting to get around the bases for
sure yeah but uh
like yeah praise and
and judgment are are strange things
we're we're such
societal creatures we like we need it or
we don't need it
for sure that's madness
well bro
you want to uh you want to get off here
and have another beer i don't call
anything else you need to talk about
nah man it's a good time it was
definitely a good time i feel like uh
i mean we say this all the time but now
that we're actually hanging out it's
like the coronavirus of a couple months
of like nobody's seeing each other
um now that unless we get a second wave
who knows but i can knock on wood but uh
it'd be great to have you up here man i
i think you're an intellectual person
i love your demeanor um obviously i love
having around just as a homie
but i like you know being able to talk
to you about things because like for
sure
i feel like you have just a level-headed
view of so many things
appreciate that i appreciate you coming
on here yeah and i love you man
love you too folks if you enjoyed the
episode
please share just follow like subscribe
any of those things whatever's relevant
to you whatever it's just a quick click
away it's not too much of an
inconvenience
and if you think it'll help somebody
else share it if you think it'll help
somebody else
i appreciate it we'll see you next
episode
you